Lately, Yor has been coming home late.
We're not the type to stick our noses
into each other's business,
so I haven't asked her about it…
I wonder what we're having for dinner
Father. When are we having dinner?
When Yor comes back home.
Bond. Predict what we're having
for dinner tonight.
I'm back.
She has a gloomy and sullen face,
and there are…
numerous cuts on her hand.
Welcome home, Mother.
I'm glad to be back, Anya.
Welcome home.
Shall we have dinner?
Oh, I'm not so hungry.
So please have dinner without me.
Okay…
Yor… are you…?
Mother is going to cry? Why?
If I fail this…
I might lose both of them.
ORIGINAL WORK BY TATSUYA ENDO
SERIALIZED ON SHUEISHA'S SHONEN JUMP PLUS
Good work, everyone.
Good work.
Hey, Camilla,
want to go out for drinks?
Oh… well…
I'll pass.
Hey, didn't you say
that you have a date tonight?
He canceled at the last minute.
Thank you!
Are we doing it again today?
But more importantly…
Are those tomatoes? They're squashed!
What are you doing, Yor?!
Hey Yor. You're working hard as always.
Thanks for having me.
This is all your fault!
If only you hadn't said that…
MISSION: 16 YOR'S KITCHEN
THREE DAYS AGO
Huh? You want to learn how to cook?
Yes. The other day I made breakfast,
but because of that,
my husband was in the bathroom all day!
That's horrible.
If this continues, our marriage
will be in danger.
Which also means my job will be in danger.
Can someone please help me
learn how to cook?
Huh?
Well…
The housekeeper cooks for us in our house.
Go to a cooking class.
I know how to open a can!
Hey, what are you guys talking about?
Oh, I see! She's really good at cooking!
Hey!
I'm begging you, Camilla!
I don't want to.
Why do I have to do it?
Oh, come on. Just teach her.
All right, let's meet at her house.
Hey there!
Therefore, I'm looking forward to
learning from you again today!
This is the worst.
Don't say that.
You'll be in charge of tasting her
dishes again! That's your responsibility!
Oh, yes, about that…
I called in one more person for that role.
Hooray! Hey, Sis!
Yuri!
I heard that I could eat
one of your home cooked meals!
Oh boy…
This is Yor's younger brother?
He seems different from the pictures--
Thank you for having me, Camilla!
Thank you for taking care of my sister.
Sure…
Is there some kind of a party
going on here today?
What? Cooking lesson?
Don't tell Loid, it's a secret.
I want to improve secretly.
She's making a meal for Lotty?
I'm having mixed feelings now.
I'm thinking of making minestrone today.
I already told you that
you buy so many unnecessary things.
What will you use this for?
I'm sorry. I thought I could make it
delicious by adding lots of things in it.
Let's start by peeling the potatoes.
All right!
How in the world does this happen
with a peeler?!
It's a pool of blood!
This weapon is so hard to handle.
A peeler isn't a weapon.
Sis, I brought a bandage.
I'm good with a knife.
Like I said, you're cutting it too small!
Just cut it normally!
You're amazing, Sis!
Hey! Why did you cut the cutting board?
That was my favorite!
I'm sorry. I'll replace it!
You're amazing, Sis.
Seriously, what's wrong with you?
How were you able to get married? Leave!
What's with this woman? She's being
rude to Sis. Should I execute her?
Yor, you're hopeless.
You should just give up.
You should divorce that handsome man.
No way…
She brought up a good point! That's right.
Break up with him!
Please, Camilla!
If Loid divorces me, then I'll be…
I'll be…
Back to worrying about getting arrested!
Hurry up and start cooking
the ingredients you chopped up.
I'll explain the seasonings after that.
Quickly make that thing,
and get out of here.
She's actually pretty nice.
If only a little cynical.
I think Camilla is a good person.
Hey!
Anyways, my first dish is complete.
Come on, Yuri! This is your time to shine!
Taste that dish for her!
Really? May I?
Thank you for the food.
It's so delicious, Sis!
This tastes so nostalgic!
Oh my!
Wait, is he throwing up?
Is it good or not?
How in the world does something
turn out like this?
Did you follow my instructions?
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry!
Hey Sis. Can I have seconds?
Minestrone was too advanced for you.
Let's make something easier
like meatballs.
Okay!
It's delicious! It's so good that
I'm breaking out in a cold sweat!
As I'm enjoying this flavor,
my childhood memories
are rushing back to me.
Wait, I'm seeing someone…
-Is it Mother?
-Stop, Yuri!
Stop for a second!
Oh, I see. Yor and her younger brother
grew up without parents.
You only had someone like this
eating your food,
and that's why your taste buds are dead.
Someone like this?!
I thought everything would be fine
as long as it was nutritious.
Yuri, I'm so glad that you
grew up healthy and well.
Hey, don't you remember
something delicious
that your parents made for you?
Just as a reference.
Yuri, do you remember anything?
Mom's cooking?
I vaguely remember her serving us
something that looked like stew.
It was so warm. I really liked it.
Oh yes, it had a fried egg on top.
All right, let's try making that.
Try to remember what it tasted like.
I think the base is a simple
southern stew.
-Whoa!
-Once it boils, turn off the heat.
I think you should add ground paprika.
Okay!
Make sure not to burn it.
Add the right amount of salt and pepper.
I understand.
You know, Yor…
something about you changed a little.
You used to look like a robot
with a bored expression on your face.
Is that right?
-I wondered if it's because I got married.
-Huh?
Why are you bragging?
You probably just changed
your make-up or something.
I'm sorry! I'm really sorry!
Now, now.
Camilla, you're a lovely lady too.
Have confidence.
What…
By the way, I'm smelling something
good for the first time!
Did you succeed in making this dish?
It's not bad.
It's delicious!
But I feel like there's something missing.
Yor, where's your hometown?
Around East Nielsberg.
If your family is from around that area,
they might have added sour cream.
I'm so exhausted now.
What is it?
Nothing. I was just thinking of
how cute you are.
Shut up.
Wait.
Okay.
It seems like he's a smart dog.
I'll start training him to be a guard dog.
Father. Anya can't follow
the "wait" command.
I'm so hungry.
Yeah.
I'm sorry for being late.
Welcome back, Yor.
What is that?
Loid.
I will be making dinner tonight!
Oh no!
You were learning how to cook?
I'm sorry for keeping it a secret.
That's why she was late…
Is this southern stew?
Yes. My mother used to make this
for us a lot.
It's done.
The fried egg kind of lost its shape, but…
Please enjoy!
It smells… safe.
The last supper.
-Delicious.
-It's delicious!
Anya likes this!
It tastes very comforting.
What's wrong, Yor?
I'm sorry.
I think I'm feeling relieved
looking at the two of you.
I thought I had to
protect this life in order to
continue as an assassin.
But having the both of you approve of me,
and seeing your laughter,
just simply makes me so happy.
This gave me a little bit of confidence,
to be the wife and mother of
the Forger family!
We'll be counting on you.
Oh, that's right! I made one more dish,
so please try that one too.
This is my original dish.
I want to eat it!
What do you want,
calling me out to a place like this?
I fell in love with a woman.
I see. Good for you. Bye.
Wait! Listen to me!
MISSION: 16
THE GREAT ROMANCE SCHEME FOR THE INFORMANT
What? You want me to give you
a fool-proof date plan?
You're a professional in that field.
The key is to do your best. Bye.
Wait, you heartless man!
You want me to sell your information
to the Secret Police?
I'm just kidding!
Oh yeah, you were asking me to
develop a new mini recording advice,
right?
I'll make that for free
as an exchange for helping me.
Okay?
Her name is Monica McBride.
She's an employee
at the cigar club on Fifth Street.
She's 25 years old.
Her birthday is September 20th.
Her blood type is O.
Her height is 162 cm,
and she weighs 46 kg.
Currently she's living together
with her mother and younger sister.
Her hobby is watching movies,
and her favorite movie is Ba Ba Berlint.
Her childhood nickname is Moppy…
Are you a stalker?
Stop looking so disgusted.
You do extensive research on people too!
Mine is for work.
You idiot!
It's a man's natural instinct
to want to know everything
about a person he's really in love with!
Since you've already gathered
so much information,
can't you handle the rest on your own?
You idiot! Even the information department
is separated into data collection,
and evaluation and analysis.
My expertise is just data collection.
You don't have to brag about it.
I'm begging you. I'm serious about this.
In order to see her,
I visit her store every day to
smoke cigars even though I don't enjoy it.
Please have mercy on this humble,
scruffy four-eyes.
I just need to analyze the information
and draft up a plan, right?
Thank you so much, Twilight!
I will call you President!
Shut up. Just wait for a moment.
All right, it's done.
I made a conversation flowchart
according to her character,
which I speculated,
based on your information.
I see.
Let's say that you asked her
question number one.
For example, her favorite food.
I wrote down four possible answers
that we can anticipate.
I see.
Then I wrote down the best response
you can give to each possible answer.
From there, the conversation branches out
with the best response you can give
for all the answers from A to D.
I see.
If you memorize this entire chart,
and read the atmosphere, as you choose
your responses appropriately…
How can I do that?!
There are thousands of responses!
First of all, I don't know how to choose
responses "appropriately."
Give me a versatile scenario that will
work universally.
If such a thing existed,
life would be a lot easier for us.
Should I disguise myself
and send you signals?
I don't want you to hear our conversation.
Then you'll have no choice but to
practice having a conversation with her.
What? With you as my partner?
That's so creepy.
I'm just kidding. Please help me!
HE PUT ON A DISGUISE
All right. I'm perfectly prepared now.
Tomorrow I will use
this strategic art of conversation
to challenge the battle with Monica.
Please look forward to my report.
You don't have to report back to me.
I'm seeing a shadow of death,
but will he be all right?
Welcome.
Thank you for coming again, Franky.
Today… is… an… auspicious day…
Excur-gen
Anya wants to go to
the playground obstacle course today.
That sounds like fun.
Oh, it's Scruffy.
Oh, the Forger family.
Anya's going to
the playground obstacle course.
That sounds fun.
Didn't you have that thing today?
Oh, the date?
Well, I was able to ask her out,
but she said that she forgot to turn off
her gas valve, so she went home.
She said she'll come with me to watch
a movie next time. Aren't you proud of me?
I have some free time today,
so I guess I'll have some drinks.
What is it?
Damn it! Are looks all that matter?
Why can't you just go with me on one date?
That firm "No!" was so mean.
Sir.
What is it? Stop talking to me.
Bring me another drink!
Your cheapest drink!
I even promised Loid that I'd make
that device for free.
I have no money and no girlfriend.
It's an 18-year-old Macallan on the rocks.
Huh? I didn't order this
damn expensive drink.
I told you I'm poor.
It's from that customer over there.
Huh?
Hey. What a coincidence.
I felt like drinking too.
Twi… I mean, Loid.
What happened to
the playground obstacle course?
Yor's taking care of it.
What? Did you come here to laugh at me?
Remember what you always used to say?
People like us
shouldn't become too attached to others.
Even if we can go out with them,
things won't work out.
Huh. It's not comforting to hear that
from someone who has a wife.
My relationship is part of a mission.
Damn it.
I'm going to get drunk today on your tab.
I'll join you.
MISSION: 17 COMMENCE OPERATION GRIFFON/
FULLMETAL LADY/OMELETTE RICE
Subtitle translation by: Lili Morita